<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Renzo C. Silva</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Renzo C. Silva</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research data management: how to get to &#39;good enough&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/research-data-management-how-to-get-to-good-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/research-data-management-how-to-get-to-good-enough/</guid>
      <description>Motivation and goals This post is fully inspired by Wilson et al. (2017), where a set of good enough practices in scientific computing are laid down. It is a mandatory annual reading. If you are doing research in the private sector or academia, and does not see any immediate benefit on adopting (any of) the steps shown therein, regardless if you hands-on programming… well, you better wake up because you may be stuck with old scientific practices that don’t fit in our current society anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal website is born!</title>
      <link>/posts/a-personal-website-is-born/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-personal-website-is-born/</guid>
      <description>It was about time&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about having a personal website for quite a while now. Somewhere to host personal and professional ideas/experiences that may deserve a dedicated outlet - aka brain dump. If any of the content presented herein is somehow useful, then I am coming one step closer to my major goal of paying back to the plethora of content contributors knitting such incredible open source communities I have been tapping knowledge from!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>IN A NUTSHELL With 12 years of proactive participation in industrially-funded R&amp;amp;D&amp;amp;I projects, I am enthusiastic about bridging academic and industrial resources to design, develop and deploy science-based solutions to real-world problems. I thrive on developing innovative analytical methods for complex mixture analysis, examining complex datasets, providing credible and meaningful assessments that create value for the project stakeholders, and presenting results in conferences, peer-reviewed papers or confidential reports. While pragmatic when dealing with the tasks at hand, innovation and groundbreaking thinking motivate me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Want Contact? Have questions or suggestions? Feel free to open an issue on GitHub or ask me on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Portfolio Demo  Coder Portfolio This theme is created based on hugo-coder.
I made it possible to tell yourself more by my change.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Title</title>
      <link>/post/template-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/template-a/</guid>
      <description>Heading Body
Cheers!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>